<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on EN</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on EN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 21:05:46 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping - Equipment</title>
      <link>/camping-equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 21:05:46 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/camping-equipment/</guid>
      <description>Beginner
 Tent (small window) sleeping bag Headl ight safety boots + thick gloves portable battery + charger + earphones igniter + flintstones knife for wood flashlight + battery + lantern (candle inside) a book + a notebook + a pen trash bags, disposable chopsticks foldable saw fire  BUSHBOX (Germany): BUSHBOX LF TITANIUM (https://m.pcstore.com.tw/tpshanshuitc/M53486177.htm) Firebox (US) 打火石 (瑞士刀: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q-tGDEEjMPo)  pan + handler Cup (can be put on the fire) dental floss + toothpaste + toothbrush foldable water bag TODO: Matches,base+pot+grid+handler, cotton bag for collecting wood,camp fork,first aid kit, sleeping pad Doing business  trowel/shovel toilet paper   If Shower is available</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment - Basics</title>
      <link>/investment-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:57:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/investment-basics/</guid>
      <description>股票 指數: 一個東西目前的價值, 加權指數,gold,oil, Agricultural products  台灣50指數,市值Top50的指數 0050 0056  傳統型基金  被動型 業務員拿你的錢幫你投資 費用高  指數股票型基金 ETF (Exchange Traded Funds)  主動型 介於基金跟股票之間 買賣方式跟股票一樣靈活 費用低,報酬低 適合新手 不用盯盤,測水溫,跟市場起伏 必須追蹤指數 指定選菜便當  期貨: 預測指數的漲跌  可槓桿 需要很多知識去預測   名詞  EPS: 淨賺多少 ROE: 公司用你的錢運轉效率  美股 美股交易券商  國外  嘉信 charles SCHWAB (已合併 TD Maeritrade) 第一理財 Firstrade (中文介面不錯) eToro (可模擬練習) Interactive Broker  國內  複委託 (國泰,玉山, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment - U.S. Stocks</title>
      <link>/investment-u.s.-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:57:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/investment-u.s.-stocks/</guid>
      <description>步驟1: 篩選  看母公司是做什麼的, 有時候賺錢的來源跟賣的產品是不同的 要看財報 公司有沒有每年越賺越多(要10年以上, 甚至金融海嘯也在賺錢的)  挑選指標  方法1  營收成長率 &amp;gt; 5% (有穩定賺錢) 現金流量佔淨利比重 &amp;gt; 80% (現金多, 不容易倒) 有息負債佔總資產比重 &amp;lt; 50%  方法2  過去10年每股盈餘 EPS 持續成長或趨勢向上, 但不能連2年衰退 過去10年股東權益報酬率 ROE 每年要 &amp;gt; 15%, 而且要穩定 負債比率須 &amp;lt; 50%  簡單方法  看股息 4% 以上就可以進場, 好公司會逐年上升 (dividend.com)   用股息估合理股價 預期股息/股價 = 4%, e.g. 星巴克股息1.44&amp;frasl;4% = 36 (是合理股價)
步驟2: 進場時機 看年線 (250天價格平均), 跌破年線就賣, 漲上年線就買, 穩定積優股就長線放著
步驟3: 現金流 長期持有, 賺到的錢再投入去滾本金</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Curry Rice</title>
      <link>/cooking-curry-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 19:24:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-curry-rice/</guid>
      <description>佛蒙特咖哩 (Apple) Preparation (2 meals)  oil rice curry blocksx2 onionsx1 (slice or dice) potaoex1 carrotx1 chicken breast  Process  Pour a bit oil into pot Add onions Fry it until it gets soft Add chicken Fry it until its colour gets changed Add carrots Add water, water should be at the same level as ingredients Boil the water Add potatoes and turn low-heat, and put on the lid Boil it for 10 minutes 撈浮沫 Turn off the stove Add curry blocks and stir them unitl melted Turn on low heat and boil them for 10 mins Adjust the stickness that you desire, if you want it sticker, cook longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Main</title>
      <link>/cooking-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 20:23:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-main/</guid>
      <description> 青椒牛肉  牛肉絲,醬油,沙茶醬,盬,酒 洋蔥+青椒+盬, 熟了加牛肉絲  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Noodles</title>
      <link>/cooking-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 20:23:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-noodles/</guid>
      <description>麻醬麵 Preparation  sesame sauce (amount: 3) peanut butter (amount: 1) soy sauce (amount: 1) vinegar (amount: 1) 香麻油 (amount: 1) warm water (amount: 1) salt chili sauce optional: sprint onions optional: cucumbers optional: spicy oil optional: garlic paste  Process noodle
 Boil water Add some salt Put noodle into pot Boil it util it&amp;rsquo;s ready Get the noodle out of pot Put some oil and cool it down  sauce</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Pasta</title>
      <link>/cooking-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 16:23:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Spaghetti brand: (recommendation: La Molisana)
 boil water add spaghetti and salt into boiling water pour some oil cook it for 8 mins (estimated time on package minus 1~2 mins, about 8~10 mins before fully cooked) take spaghetti out, and pour some oil (to prevent it form sticking to each other) get some water out of pot with a bowl for later use)  Classic Tomato Spaghetti Preparation  salt olive oil spaghetti basil garlics onions beef minces (optional) tomato sauce  Process  Cook noodle first, don&amp;rsquo;t add too much salt, because cheese and guanciale is satly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Fried rice</title>
      <link>/cooking-fried-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 22:17:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-fried-rice/</guid>
      <description>Regular fried rice Preparation  Oil 2 egg (beat the eggs in the bowl) Rice (seperate it before cooking)  Cook rice (rice:water = 1:1) Rest the rice and let it cool down Put it into fridge for 1 night in order to make it less sticky  (optional) Minced garlics (optional) Minced onions (optional) Julienne the vegetable (lettuces, carrots, cabbage, etc.) (optional) Mushrooms Soy sauce Salt + Black pepper 2 spring onions  Process  (turn on low heat) Pour oil into pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Vegetables</title>
      <link>/cooking-vegetables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 22:17:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-vegetables/</guid>
      <description>Stir-Fried Water spinach (空心菜) Preparation  Oil Chillies x 1 (small pieces) Garlic x 6 (small pieces) Water spinach (3-4 pieces) Salt  Process  (turn on high heat) Pour oil into pan Put chillies + garlics (stir-fry it until the colour of garlics turning darker) Put water spinach into pan and stir-fry it until soft Sprinkle salt over water spinach Keep stir-fry it, but do not cook it too long  References  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking - Steak</title>
      <link>/cooking-steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 23:59:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cooking-steak/</guid>
      <description>牛排 種類  菲力: 牛最少動的部份, 口感最軟, 瘦肉多, 建議 3 分 沙朗/助眼: 中間有明顯油筋, 油花多, 建議 5 分 紐約客: 形狀狹長, 筋有嚼勁, 建議 7 分 丁骨: 兩邊分別是菲力跟紐約客,  挑選  牛排要夠厚, 煎久了才不會乾 要帶有油花, 維持多汁 (建議沙朗)  材料  奶油 迷迭香(rosemary) 或百里香(thyme) (建議用 thyme) 橄㰖油 大蒜 塩 (粗粒) 黑胡椒 (粗粒) 吸水紙 平底鍋 (用鑄鐵鍋最好) 溫度計  完美的牛排  外層是深色的脆皮(由高溫引起梅納反應形成的焦脆皮) 裡面是軟嫩多汁  順序 前置作業
 讓肉靜置 20 ~ 60 mins, 讓它接近室溫 調味每一面都先灑塩再灑黑胡椒 (可以用手壓一壓把調味推進去) 將大蒜壓扁, 不需要剝皮  開始煎</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IELTS</title>
      <link>/ielts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 17:49:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ielts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  IELTS雅思考試共分聽、說、讀、寫四項科目。早上9AM起進行聽力、閱讀、寫作，約在中午完成；下午則依序進行口說考試。 不論IELTS雅思考試或IELTS for UKVI英國簽證雅思考試，均分Academic學術及General Training一般訓練兩組，兩組的聽力與口說考題是相同的，閱讀與寫作的題目則因組別而異。  General Training (unorganised) IELTS
Writing Task 2, Listening and Speaking are the same for both IELTS Academic and IELTS general.
Writing task 2 is an essay. You will be given an essay question to answer in 40 minutes by writing at least 250 words.
The only difference between the two tests is Writing Task 1 and Reading.
[Writing Task 1] General Write a letter in one of the following styles: * Formal (to someone you do not know) * Semi-formal (to someone you know formally) * Informal (to friend or family) You get 20 minutes to complete both of these tasks and must write at least 150 words for each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 20:56:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/misc/</guid>
      <description>Tips for speaking  FOCUS less on accuracy, and more on fluency. PRETEND you don&amp;rsquo;t know your native language. THINK in English always. FOCUS on the English you need to use. COMMIT to the no Mandarin rule in life.  Works  MAKE sentences to describe environment in your head at any time. RECAP your day. Play synonym game DO JAM (just a minute) exercise.  Regular expression  In order to fix typing mistake, find the lines that don&amp;rsquo;t start with *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phrase-verbs</title>
      <link>/phrase-verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 16:53:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phrase-verbs/</guid>
      <description>go go into detail 詳述；逐一細說 (e.g.) I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into detail about how I get on with her
get  get up  stand up (e.g.) If you fall, you should always get up and try again. get dressed  getup means clothes get down  sit down, duck enjoy the music/party 難過 (e.g) That movie really got me down. I hate watching sad movies about animals.  = depress = make sad   get away  leave go on vacation  getaway means vacation (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clause</title>
      <link>/clause/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 11:17:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clause/</guid>
      <description>基本5種句型  sub : (What you do in your free time) is your business. SC : Tom ins&amp;rsquo;t (what you would call friendly). Obj : She said (that) she was sorry. =&amp;gt; that 省略因為 that 不用當主詞，主詞已經有 she 了，所以可以直接省略 Obj of prep : I don&amp;rsquo;t worry about (what other think). Obj of V : I really want to believe (that tomorrow will be better). nc : He told me (I should wait).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conjunction</title>
      <link>/conjunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 03:17:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/conjunction/</guid>
      <description>Conjunction  With &amp;hellip; = because of &amp;hellip; (e.g.) With exams approaching, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to review your class notes. 隨著考試臨近，復習一下你的課堂筆記是個不錯的主意。 Once &amp;hellip; 一旦 For &amp;hellip;  由於.. (e.g.) For some inexplicable reason, he&amp;rsquo;s decided to cancel the project. 由於某種無法解釋的原因，他決定取消這個專案。 以.. 來說 (e.g.) For me,  Because So Although But However Therefore Through (e.g.) Through a process of deduction, 經過一番仔細推斷 During Furthermore, 而且 (e.g.) Furthermore, children cannot judge between right or wrong by themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview</title>
      <link>/interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 21:51:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/interview/</guid>
      <description>Interview Small talk phrases  Thanks for inviting me to interview Is the position based in this office/building? How many people work here?
 The offices are impressive
 What a great location
 I see you have an open plan office/ staff canteen.
 The weather : chilly / mild
  topics
 Q : The traffic / your journey ? A: Not bad. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me too long Q : Where are you from?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preposition</title>
      <link>/preposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 22:42:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preposition/</guid>
      <description>How to use in sentences?  (level) China is actively pumping carbon into the environment on an enormous scale. (on something) check out our video on the conflict (on something) He is a world-renowned expert on food safety. (comparison) The city of Paris is pratically synonymous with French. (because of) The city remains a hub for food, commerce and culture, with world-renowned destinations (direction) The area to the right of Seine River, better known as the Right Bank, &amp;hellip; (reach) The city&amp;rsquo;s population had grown to nearly three million people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced</title>
      <link>/advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 22:18:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/advanced/</guid>
      <description>Writing - sentence types  simple : 1 indepent clause  Layla studied biology. 或 =&amp;gt; My friend Layla studied biology in university. Even with the weather being that nasty, the couple and their families decided to go ahead with the wedding as planned.  Phrase : Even with the weather being that nasty S: the couple and their families V: decided O: to go ahead with the wedding as planned   compound : 2 indepent clauses join by conjuction  I arrived at the office at 9, and my assistant came 10 minutes later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verb</title>
      <link>/verb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:37:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/verb/</guid>
      <description>go through sth 經歷(不好的事) (e.g.) I&amp;rsquo;ve been going through a bad patch recently involve 含有  Fluency of languages involve listening, speaking, reading and writing. （語言流利包含『聽』『說』『讀』『寫』四個要素，缺一不可） The duties of tour guides involve the introduction of attractions. Involve表示邏輯中組成一個大團體中不可或缺絕對要具備的超級重要元素  occur to 發生  This doesn&amp;rsquo;t occur to most people.  improvise 即興做;即興表演 be addressed 被處理 (e.g.) The problem of climate change should be addressed with the same immediacy as Ebola or ISIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference</title>
      <link>/difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:23:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/difference/</guid>
      <description>by / with is used to answer &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo;  by + Ving  I learn English by watching YouTube.  by + N (transportation and communication) without any article (a, the):  I&amp;rsquo;ll go by bus. I&amp;rsquo;ll contact you by email.  with + N(body parts, tools, instrument)  I think with my brain. I cleaned the floor with a mop. I ate dinner with a fork.   raise vs rise vs arise  raise, raised, raised (Object required) : They raised the price rise, rose, risen (No Object): Please rise for the national anthem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation</title>
      <link>/conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:19:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/conversation/</guid>
      <description>on a whim 衝頭的念頭  We booked the trip on a whim You see resolutions can be made on a whim  bear with me = listening to me in need 當(誰)有需要 (e.g.) Being kind is helping those in need. 善良就是幫助那些有需要的人 get up to 做(壞事) (e.g.) What are you getting up to ? To my surprise / unexpected 竟然 (出乎意料)  To my surprise, she wrote a thank you letter and sent it to the store after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phrase</title>
      <link>/phrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:09:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/phrase/</guid>
      <description>follow suit 仿效 (e.g.) When one airline reduces its prices, the rest soon follow suit. by no means = not at all (e.g.) The product of this hard work is by no means simply a symbolic gesture. not so much sth as sth 與其說是…還不如說是…  I lay down not so much to sleep as to think. 我躺下來與其說是要睡覺，倒不如說是要思考。 They&amp;rsquo;re not so much lovers as friends. 他們與其說是戀人，不如說是朋友。 I don&amp;rsquo;t feel angry so much as sad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic</title>
      <link>/basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 21:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basic/</guid>
      <description>A period of time  in the past time, 在過去 for the past few days 過去幾天以來 over the past 40 years 在過去40年間 e.g. I&amp;rsquo;ve been here for over ten years. in a few months 幾個月後 for the first couple of weeks 頭幾週 For decades 幾十年以來 take a moment 花點時間 (e.g.) I want you to take a moment to look at this sentence. in a second 一下子 a few days ago / the other day / a few days ahead of {the event} 幾天前 year over year 一年又一年 in a course of time 過一段時間後 (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>